I knew it can't be...
안 될줄 알면서
but I dreamed of a happy ending.
해피엔딩을 꿈꿨습니다.
Should we just...
우리 그만
break up?
헤어질까요?
- Summon to the Grave - [Goblin Summon Special Part 2]
쓸쓸하고 찬란하신 도깨비 소환 스페셜 2부 저승으로 소환
[January 24, 2017]
2017년 1월 24일
Hello, viewers. Good to see you.
시청자 여러분 안녕하세요 반갑습니다.
- Hello. Good to see you. This is Yoo In Na. - This is Lee Dong Wook.
안녕하세요, 반갑습니다 유인나 입니다.
Continued from yesterday, we get to see you again.
어제에 이어서 또 이렇게 만나뵙게 됐네요
- Nice to see you. - It's nice to see you.
-반갑습니다.
This is my happy face, for real. I'm truly happy.
이거 되게 반가운 표정이에요 진심으로.
Welcome! It's your first time seeing Part 2, right?
대환영! 어서와. 2부는 처음이지?
This is the Goblin Summon Special Part 2 and at the same time,
네, 자 도깨비 소환 스페셜 두 번째이자
the last episode of all.
마지막이기도 한 이시간
We prepared many things, more than yesterday, didn't we?
오늘은 더 정말 많은 것들이 준비되어 있죠?
That's right.
그렇습니다 여러분들이
According to what you have requested, everything about Goblin,
보내주신 요청사항에 맞춰서 도깨비에 대한 모든것을
for the first time in the nation, for the first in a lifetime,
국내 최초 이승 최초
we are going to show you every bit of it.
탈탈 털어서 보여드릴 예정입니다.
Time to meet Goblin to the bone!
도깨비의 뼛속까지 만나보는 시간!
Goblin Summon Special, [Does she mean Gong Yoo Hyung's bones?]
도깨비 소환 스페셜
Part 2. Summon to the Grave.
제 2부 저승으로 소환
Shall we officially begin now?
본격적으로 시작해 볼까요?
Pray with all your heart.
간절하게 빌어
Then we will show you all the behind-the-scenes
그러면 어디에서 공개되지 않은
that have never been aired.
비하인드도 보여줄거야.
You resemble a fennec fox.
사막여우를 닮았네
Good job. [Airing all the omitted scenes!]
잘했어!
Pull me. [Heart attack warning. Even the behind-the-kissing-scene is beautiful.]
입맞춤
- I really want to ask you something. - Then, quickly go ahead.
-저 꼭 물어보고 싶은데 있단 말이에요. -그럼 빨리해.
[Intense analysis of Goblin details of everything you're curious about]
도깨비 속 깨알 궁금증 전격 해부
That was a plate from Louis XIV's era.
방금 그거 루이 14세때 접시다.
The viewers don't think it's a CG.
우리 시청자들은 CG라고 생각을 못해.
Our show is all about CG, though.
우리 드라마는 CG드라마 인데.
Just like there is no tomorrow. [No more waiting, no, no...]
내일이 없는 것처럼.
This is perfect.
완벽하다!
[It begins now.]
소환 스페션 2부. 지금 바로 시작합니다.
The first thing we are going to show you is...
첫번째 최초공개 해드릴 내용은
it's a brief request that was sent by
아이디 '메이드인헤븐'님께서
ID: Made in Heaven.
짧고 굵게 보내주신 요청사항입니다.
Shut up and give us all the omitted scenes!
'닥치고 누락 장면들 다 풀어 놓거라!'
I agree!
옳소!
"Made in Heaven" refers to Grim Reaper's
메이드 인 헤븐은 또 저승이 모자에..
hat... you know?
예 그걸 말하는 거잖아요?
Like the Grip Reaper's hat that made you invisible when worn,
쓰면 안보이던 저승이 모자처럼
we are going to show you
시청자 분들께는 보여드리지 못했던
all the omitted scenes.
누락 장면들
For a long time, we gathered everything.
아주 길게 원 없이 한 번 준비해봤습니다.
A.K.A. Miscellaneous omitted scenes. [Entire Omitted.zip]
일명 기타누락신
I heard that we have a pile of those omitted scenes.
파일들이 잔뜩 쌓여있다고 하는데요
- You are curious, aren't you? - Yes, I'm very curious.
-너무 궁금하죠? -너무 궁금합니다.
Let's go check them out right now.
지금부터 바로 확인해보시죠!
It must be fun.
재밌겠다, 재밌겠다.
[From hardcore acting scenes]
아아아악!
Did Dong Wook do this? [Sweet and Scary]
동욱이가 그랬어?!
You should do a cameo. [To the moments with very special guests]
야, 까메오 한 번 하고 가라.
You shouldn't. You are a grim reaper. [A collection of omitted scenes that have never been aired!]
안 되지~
I don't know. They will choose something.
아, 몰라 알아서 쓰시겠지.
[Miscellaneous omitted scenes]
기타누락신
♬  Starlight is shining down ♬ [Perfect and brilliant Gong kkaebi(goblin), do you still have something left to show us...?]
♫ 별 빛이 내린다 샤라랄라랄랄라  ♫
[Thump, thump. Stop moving, heart.]
♫ 샤라랄라랄랄라 ♫
[Heart attack warning]
♫ 샤라랄라랄랄라  ♫
[Here are the omitted scenes of Goblin. Ready to fall in love again.]
재입덕 준비
[Funny scenes: Goblin]
#유쾌하신 도깨비
Aren't you afraid of god?
하늘이 두렵지 않으십니까?!
General! [Ready to show off his charm]
-넘어지고.. -장군!!
[Hahahaha]
하하하하
It's like Humor 1st Street (comedy show).
유머일번지 같잖아 이건!
General...
장군!!
Ow... Ow, it hurts. That Hyung is funny. [Very serious. Getting ready to face a tragic death.]
세상진지
Ow...
아...
[Please be gentle.jpg]
살살 찔러줘.jpg
[Goblin can feel the pain too.jpg]
도깨비도 아프다.jpg
[Don't want to die...but I should.jpg]
죽기는 싫구나... 속도 없이.jpg
[Goblin shooting the fighting scene]
폭풍열연
Cut. Cut!
-컷!
Let's call it okay.
-OK 할게요. -네.
What do you mean you'd call it okay?
OK 할게요는 뭐야 OK 할게요는
It doesn't feel right because you said that.
OK 할게요 그러니까 찝찝하잖아.
I was thinking the same thing just now.
나도 지금 그 생각하고 있었는데.
[I will show what OK is.]
지금부터 OK가 뭔지 보여주겠다
Hey, wait. Wait. Again. [Determined]
야,야,야 잠깐만 다시!
- Again. - I will show you some other day.
다시해
[Laughing is okay~]
하하하하
He ran away.
도망갔네.
[Sunbae-like_Goblin]
#선배미_뽐내신_도깨비
[ Kim Shin and Ga Shin shooting together for the first time]
도깨비 김신과 가신의 촬영날
It's an honor to get to work with Gong Yoo Sunbae, who was in Train to Busan, viewed by more than 10 million people. [Goblin, first reading day]
부산행을 찍은 천만배우 공유
[Nerve-wrecking first meeting with a "10-million actor" Gong Yoo
영화 '부산행' 천만배우 공유님💓과의 떨렸던 첫 만남
You can call me Uncle or Hyung, depending on your mood.
삼촌 아니면 뭐 기분에 따라 형.
Since I'm not married yet. I heard he went to the last phase of Train to Busan audition.
아직 내가 장가 안갔으니까. 부산행 최종까지 갔었대.
- It was originally written as a son in the beginning. - I can work on the ship and... [Rehearsing before shooting!]
원래는 아들 촬영이였거든 원래는.
- get some food. - You should look here, too.
촬영 전 호흡 맞춰보는 중!
Good job. [Very proud] [Saw fireflies? Realistic acting.]
잘했어.
- He's a really good sunbae. - Right, he's nice and sweet.
-좋은 선배네요 정말. -맞아요, 다정해요.
He should be nice to me, too.
나한테도 좀 저러지..
[Shooting the first time Kim Shin and Ga Shin meet]
도깨비 김신과 가신의 첫 만남 촬영 중
Please...
절...
accept my bow.
받으십시오..
[Awkward. Awkward.]
어색 어색
Cut.
컷!
[Since the shooting just began, It's difficult for Ji Hoon to concentrate]
촬영 초반 감정 이입이 쉽지 않던 지훈
Imagine where everyone you love is gone.
지훈이가 진짜로 사랑하고 좋아하는 사람이 없어졌다고 생각해봐.
Mom, Dad, Sibling... [Sunbae-like charisma. Gong Yoo helps him to concentrate and get the right emotion.]
누구있지? 엄마, 아빠..
You don't need to sob. Sincerely feeling sad to the heart is more important than anything.
눈물은 안 흘려도 돼. 마음이 진짜로 슬픈게 중요한거야.
Turn around when you are ready, Ji Hoon.
지훈이 감정 좋을 때 돌아 앉아주세요.
He's ready. [He suddenly begins to sob.]
-준비됐습니다 -하나,둘,셋, 큐!
[The feelings of a little grandson who lost his grandfather]
할아버지를 잃은 어린 손자의 마음
Grandpa...
할아버지!
Aigoo..
아이구..
He's doing it very well. [These two are mesmerized by his crying scene.]
-아이고.. -잘한다, 잘한다.
[Receiving his emotion, Kim Shin continues his acting]
감정을 받아 연기를 이어나가는 김신
You are...
자네가
my first punishment, it seems.
내가 받는 첫 번째 벌인 모양이다.
Please...
절..
accept my bow. [Used a wrong expression]
받아주시옵소서.
"Please accept my bow." Again.
-'절 받으십시오' 다시. -절
- Please accept my bow. - Again.
-받으십시오 -다시 -절
Please accept my bow.
받으십시오
- Like that... - He told him to do it again in a very gentle way.
-저렇게.. -저렇게 다정하게 다시 하라고 얘기해주고
- The chemistry between the two... - Wow, they're so great...
-두 분의 호흡이 참... -우와, 진짜 멋지네요.
He did very well.
아주 잘했네요.
Cut. It's good. [Crying scene is complete with Sunbae-like charisma.]
컷, OK요. OK입니다.
Yes, we'll continue...
선배미로 완성된 오열 연기 OK
[Good job~]
잘 했어~
- She's my guest! - It's my house!
-내 집이야!
It's my room.
제 방이에요!
We will put up some 19th century romantic art style wallpaper on this side [Eun Tak has a long line]
이 쪽에대가 19세기 낭만파 벽지를 바르고
and we will put a pastel-toned fireplace
요쪽에다가 파스텔톤의
over here. To be fair.
벽난로를 놓죠 뭐, 사이좋게..
Then for now...
그럼 일단 오늘은...
[Eun Tak forgot her line for a second]
순간 대사를 잊어버린 은탁
Should I sleep on the sofa in the living room? [It's already a blooper!]
거실 쇼파에서 자면 되나요?
If you are uncomfortable having me in the living room, the flower garden is fine, too.
제가 거실에 있는게 불편하면 밖에 화단도 괜찮아요.
I'm not in the position to discriminate where to sleep. [Acting like nothing happened]
제가 누울 자리 가릴 처지가 아니라서...
You barely made it.
참 연명한다.
Taking one step and another one... [She tried to do a CPR to the dying lines but failed.]
한 발, 한 발...
But there are many scenes
근데 저런식으로해서
she did that and got OKs.
OK받은게 되게 많아요 은탁이는!
They can edit it out.
아, 왜냐면 편집해서 쓰면 되니까.
She makes it seem like she didn't make a mistake. She does it naturally and well.
자연스럽게 NG가 아닌 것처럼 아주 잘 해.
Even if you do that, they won't use it. Just cut and do it again.
어짜피 그렇게 해도 안쓸건데 컷하고 다시 할게요, 하면 되지.
Ah, I got caught. [Embarrassing, embarrassing]
아우, 파악당했어.
- The last line is too hard. - "I can't be choosy..."
마지막 대사가 너무 어려워요.
- Relax your lips. Loosen up. - Okay.
-입을 조금 풀어. -네! -힘을 빼고.
- It's because you're trying to enunciate every word. That's why it's hard.
그 단어를 너무 꼭꼭 찝어서 하려 그러니까 그 단어가 어려운거야.
I can't really be choosy right now. [Go Eun does a better job after listening to the advice]
-제가 지금 누울 자리를 가릴 처지가 아니라서.. -진짜야.
[# Multidimensional artist_Goblin]
종합예술인이신_도깨비
Multidimensional artist. Yeah, right. He's a multidimensional artist.
종합예술인, 그렇죠 종합예술인이죠.
He can do anything.
못하는게 없죠.
[Kim Shin is writing a will]
도깨비 김신이 유서를 쓰는 장면
[We heard that he put his artistic spirit in every letter...]
그의 한 글자 한 글자에는 예술혼이 담겨있다는데...
Director Lee: You are good at writing.
엄청 잘 쓰는데?
People who are bad(?) at studying have good handwriting.
원래 공부 못 하는 애들이 글씨를 잘 써.
-  Did you capture it? This, this? - Yes, I'm filming.
-찍었어요? -예, 찍고 있어요. -요거, 요거, 요거?
I used to do caligraphy until I was in the 3rd grade. [Nice Mr. Eung Bok. I love you, director.]
초등학교 3학년때 까지는 서예했어.
Director Lee: It's so annoying. He looks good sitting and standing.
짜증나 앉은 것도 멋있고 서있는 것도 멋있고
He's cool whatever he does. [He looks cool whether he's sitting down or standing up]
멋있는걸 어떡해.
Kids don't like to hear that. [He's good at calligraphy and looks cool whether he's standing or sitting down]
애들이 그런 얘기하면 싫어하더라고. 나를 싫어하더라고.
But what Director Lee said is true though. [Goblin - hotness = 0. Even Grim Reaper agrees!]
근데 뭐 이응복 감독님의 저 말씀이 사실이죠.
He looks great.
아! 너무 멋있죠.
♬ You're so beautiful. You're beautiful. I said you're beautiful ♬ [Exactly... how handsome are you?]
♫ 너 정말 이쁘다 이쁘다 이쁘다니까  ♫
[Looks like a sitting-statue when he's seated]
♫  왜 내 말 믿지 않는 건데 왜 ♫
[Looks like a standing-statue when he's up]
♫ 말하고 말하고 아무리 말해도 ♫
[Goblin does art with his entire body]
♫ 화난 듯한 너의 그 표정 ♫
Reason for Goblin's omitted scenes: #Heart attack_warning [#My_girlfriend_should_close_her_eyes]
도깨비짤 누락사유
Ow, you poked me.
아, 찔렸어.
[There is something special at Goblin shooting sight?]
도깨비 현장에는 특별한 것이 있다?!
[Overflowing ad-libs & bloopers]
넘쳐나는 애드리브 NG 장면
[Personally saved video clips revealed]
#개인 소장 유발 영상 공개
[# Those_Ad-libs]
#애드리브가_뭐길래
- There are so many ad-libs. - There are so many.
-애드리브..너무 많아요, 너무 많아요. -아, 너무 많아서.
Don't mention anything that involves the letters "ch."
'ㅊ' 들어가는 얘기 아무것도 하지 마세요!
Hey, you got the first ("Cheot") question wrong.
-야, 그 첫문제 틀렸어. -하지마시라구요.
Is your bed ("Chim-dae") comfortable?
너 침대는 쓸만하고?
Oh, right ("Ah-Cha"), sorry. Cha, cha, cha together.
아차, 미안~ 다함께 차차차~
[No one can stop this naughty goblin.]
장난꾸러기 도깨비는 못 말려~
Ready, cue! [Shin Tak couple is watching Train to Busan at a theater]
큐!
[Goblin acts with passion as he screams]
괴성(?)담은 도깨비의 열연
[Mister, Eun Tak is almost dying of laughter. TT TT]
아저씨~ 은탁이 웃겨 죽어요 ㅠㅠ
I heard that it was difficult for Eun Tak to act because he screamed so much.
찍을 때 은탁이 너무 힘들었대요. 하도 소리 질러 가지고.
[2nd trial]
하이, 큐!
[He brought his "scared" acting to a whole new level.]
아아아악!
[Blooper! Impossible to act her emotions!]
NG! 감정이입 불가
[How am I supposed to act~!]
아, 잠깐만!
[This scene, Sunny slipped and almost fell to the ground]
어머!
[Swoosh]
휙~!
[Grim Reaper's kick full of naughtiness]
아하하하!
[Goblin is preparing to say good-bye]
아! 카드! 이거 진짜 나 주는 거야 삼촌?
[This scene, which Goblin is handing Deok Hwa his credit card.]
잘 크느라 고생했다.
I love you. [Pat, pat]
사랑해요...
This kid...
이 자식이..
[Ad-lib out of nowhere, Goblin is trying "forehead-kiss"]
돌발 애드리브. 이마키스 시도하는 도깨비
What are you doing? Put your clothes on. [Goblin & Reaper getting ready to go out to Play Store]
뭐 해? 옷 입고 와.
Oh, right. It's freezing, freezing outside.
어, 어 추워, 추워.
Freezing, freezing... [Goblin burst out laughing because of Grim Reaper's ad-lib]
추워 추워~ 저승사자의 애드리브에 빵 터진 도깨비
Cut. It's a cut.
컷~
- Do I feel coldness? I freeze everything, you know. - I don't know.
나도 춥나? 나는 막 다 얼리고 다니는데?
I'm not sure either. [Truth will be revealed next lifetime?]
-맞네. -나도 잘 모르겠어...
[He's proud of his ad-libs]
애드리브 열연에 흐뭇한 장본인
There were so many of Dong Wook's ad-libs.
이동욱씨 애드립 정말 너무 많아요.
When we were filming together, there were so many ad-libs. [He gets new ideas of ad-libs when he's with Goblin]
둘이 같이 있을 때 애드립이 진짜 많았는데.
- You got a text. - No, it's the door bell.
-문자 왔다. -아니야, 초인종 소리야.
What? [Could it be a ghost? Door bell made them scared]
뭐?
[Surprised by the doorbell...]
초인종으로 놀란 가슴
[Let's overcome with Buddhism.]
진짜..
[Already knocked out]
이미 KO
Was it that funny?
그렇게 웃겼어?
[This scene, in which Grim Reaper comforts Goblin.]
저승사자가 도깨비를 위로해주는 장면
Ow, you poked me. Ow, you poked me.
아, 아! 찔렸어!
[Shocked by the surprise attack, Hahahahaha.]
기습공격에 당황
Ah, why? [Why don't you go along with it? You should've been prepared.]
아, 왜!
I thought you would say things like, "Oh, does it hurt?" [Only thinking about ad-libs during break]
아까 형이 그런거 할 줄 알았어, '어, 아파?' 뭐 이런거.
Ah, really... I'm sorry. Honestly, I wasn't prepared.
내가 미안하다. 사실은 대비를 못했다.
- Ouch. - I'm sorry.
미안해..
Thanks for going along with my ad-libs. [Seriously, you shouldn't get your sword out anywhere.]
야, 너는!
[Limp. limp.]
절뚝 절뚝
Please forgive me. [Grim Reaper is asking Goblin for forgiveness]
용서해줘.
[Seriously taping their first meeting in nine years]
진지하게 촬영 중인 9년 만의 만남
You should get a haircut first.
이발부터 해야겠다.
Trends come and go.
유행은 돌고 돌아.
[Goblin's hair is in Goryeo era style~]
아무 말도 하지 마.
Goryeo style...
고려시대 스타일~
At a such emotional scene... [Trying to control his emotions. I'm serious.]
지금 이 감정이...
You should get a haircut first. [Serious, shooting again]
이발부터 해야겠다.
Are you jealous?
부럽냐?
[The Grim Reaper stops the Goblin's ad-lib]
도깨비 애드리브 저지하는 저승사자
You are not letting me to do ad-libs because you couldn't do it earlier, aren't you?
너 아까 네가 할 때 애드립 못해가지고 지금 심술나가지고 나 못하게 막는거지?
Maybe?
조금?
[# Power of vitamins]
#비타민의_힘
Power of vitamins...? [Thinking]
음..
Power of vitamins?
비타민의 힘...?
What is it? Ah!!
-비타민의 힘? 뭐지? 아! -아!
What is it?
-무슨 일이야? -이건 신경 쇠약
This is for bipolar disorder.
이건 조울증..
Gong Yoo Hyung just pretended to swallow them.
이렇게해서 공유형은 드시는 시늉만 했어요.
My uncle...
우리 삼촌 대체!
[Grim Reaper needed the pills because of Sunny]
써니 때문에 약이 필요했던 저승사자
If I cried after meeting a woman for the first time... what could that be about?
어떤 여자를 처음보고 눈물이 흘렀다면, 그건 뭘까?
[Chew, chew]
와그작 와그작
[1000mg super sour vitamins]
사실 엄청 신 맛의 1000mg 비타민
Cut.
컷!
Eww~
우웩~
One of them is a vitamin.
- 아, 저 웃음 터질 뻔했어. - 야, 하나 비타민이야!
[Grim Reaper is in pain after chewing the vitamin]
생비타민 씹어 먹고 괴로워하는 저승사자
Was it sour? Very sour?
셔? 저거 씹으면 셔요 엄청?
It's beyond sour, it's bitter.
신 걸 넘어서 써요!
Oh, I see.
오~
This is why we just swallow vitamins.
아, 이래서 이걸 삼켜 먹는구나.
Right.
어으!
[Viewers, please swallow vitamins with water.]
시청자 여러분은 물과 삼켜 드세요 😭
It's too sour, too sour.
아, 너무 셔, 너무 셔.
I'm fully charged with vitamins now.
덕분에 비타민 충전 됐어.
Don't you have to eat some more, though?
더 드셔야 되는거 아니에요?
Yes, I do. Once or twice maybe?,
더 먹어야죠, 뭐 한 두번 더 먹겠죠.
[Vitamins eating show? Eat and eat, keeps eating.]
비타민 먹방?
[Already in a half coma]
이미 반은 혼수 상태
Cut. Okay.
오케이, 컷!
[Running immediately after hearing "cut"]
컷 소리에 불꽃 질주
Someone scolded me for doing something no one asked me to do. Hear that?
이 때 한소리 들었죠, 시키지도 않은거 해가지고. 이거 봐 지가 한다고 했다고.
It's always like that.
한참 그렇지 뭐.
Why would you try so hard?
왜 갑자기 불꽃 연기를 해?
Just like there is no tomorrow. [What was the reason for trying so hard?]
왜 이런걸 직접 먹고 그래.
I wanted to express it differently.
왜 그랬냐면, 다르게 표현하고 싶었어요.
Their depressions... If I swallow the pills,
예, 둘의 우울함을 단순히 그냥 삼킨다로만 끝나면은
it's no different, you know?
-예, 좋았어요. -그 차별성이 안생기니까.
[The Goblin and the Grim Reaper argue back and forth in front of the house]
집 앞에서 티격태격하는 도깨비와 저승사자
What are you doing?
무슨 짓이야!
What, why?
왜, 뭐!
I'm being competitive.
승부욕이야!
[Is it due to vitamins? His acting is exceptionally powerful.] What am I if you just leave like that?
네가 그러고 들어가면 내가 뭐가 돼!
What is it? What can I not do? [Rehearsing as though they're shooting for real]
뭔데, 내가 뭘 못했는데!
[The taping begins. Getting too close physically in their acting]
본격 촬영 시작
- What are you doing? - What, why? I'm being competitive.
- 뭔 짓이야? - 왜, 뭐? 승부욕이야. 어딜 들어가?
Get lost. Go.
멀리 가, 멀리!
What am I if you just leave like that?
네가 그러고 들어가면 내가 뭐가 돼!
[Were the vitamins effective?]
진가를 발휘한 비타민 연기(?)
My acting is good.
내가 봐도 연기 좋네
[# Bloopers that even God can't stop]
신도 못막는 NG
[Eun Tak, who lost her memories, meets Goblin in Canada]
기억을 잃은 은탁이 캐나다에서 도깨비를 만나는 장면
[What was omitted from this scene?]
이 장면에서 누락된 영상은?
It will look so weird if you come through this door.
여기서 나오면 진짜 이상할거야.
There is no door knob, you know.
아니, 이게 손잡이가 없잖아.
You can't go in once you are out.
다시 못 들어가!
It's funny. Let's try it.
야, 이거 웃긴다 해보자, 해보자.
Cue! [1st trial]
큐!
[Closing slowly...]
스르르륵~
[Failed because the door closed very slowly]
문이 늦게 닫혀서 NG
This doesn't close. It should close right away.
야, 이게 안 닫히네! 바로 닫혀야 되는데.
Cue!
큐!
[2nd trial!]
2차 시도!
[Would it work this time?]
과연 이번엔?
[Worked!]
성공!
[What's the secret behind the door?]
빨리 닫힌 문의 비밀은?
[There was a staff hiding in the corner]
숨어있는 스태프 발견!
[The scene was complete with the staff's help]
스태프의 손짓까지 더해져 완성된 장면
Ah, today is so strange.
아, 나 오늘 너무 이상하다 진짜.
- There are many scenes like that. - Yes, there are many hidden contributions.
-이런 게 진짜 많아요. -숨은 공신이 정말 많죠.
[Eun Tak is blowing on a dandelion in Canada]
캐나다에서 민들레 홀씨를 부는 은탁
[What's with the dandelion flying away... The staff and their equipment all at work!]
흩날리는 민들레가 뭐길래... 스태프와 도구까지 총동원!
Cut.
커트!
We will try one more time.
다시 한 번 갈게요.
They kept flying into the frame. [Failed because the seeds kept flying in even though Eun Tak was done blowing]
뭐야? 계속 날라와.
I cannot control it... I'm sorry.
이게 내 맘대로 되지 않아, 미안해!
She's done blowing on it here but it still flies in this direction.
다 불었는데 계속 날라와.
[Showing her cute aegyo to cheer the tired staff up]
고생했던 스태프를 위한 은탁의 애교 발사~
[Cheer up, everyone
모두 힘내세용~💕
Who are you with this time? [Correct line] Who are you looking at right now? [Blooper]
이번엔 누구랑 있는거야, 넌 또.. 이번엔 넌 대체 누굴 보고 있는거니?
♬ Who are you looking at right now? [Everyone singing along]
-NG! -넌 대체 누굴 보고 있는거야~ 내가 찾는 여인~
What is it this time? [Eun Tak alone can't get used to it]
이 노랜 뭐지? 이 노랜..
♬ Who are you looking at right now? [Sing along here, too]
-넌 대체 누굴보고 있는거야~ -넌 대체 누굴보고 있는거니~
If you know this song, we can tell your age.
이 노래 알면 써니 씨 나이 다 나와요.
- What is this song, by the way? - It's the TV show Jealousy soundtrack.
-이게 뭐죠 근데? -질투, 드라마 질투.
I see. [Okay, I handled it well.]
아~
[Goblin got excited over the 20th century tv show]
이번엔 대체 누구랑 있는거야, 그 다음에...
- At the end, the camera went round and round, 360 degrees. - I know, I know.
마지막에 막 360도 카메라 돌고 막!
They kissed and stuff.
둘이 키스하고 막!
[Goblin's fashion is being checked by Grim Reaper]
저승사자에게 패션 검사 받는 도깨비
Action.
액션.
Wait. [Tried running fast but failed.]
잠깐만!
He seemed shy when we filmed this.
되게 쑥스러워 하시더라고요 이거 찍을 때.
[Orabeoni is cute~]
흐흐흐흐
Think of this as the outfit I'll be wearing when I leave this house. [Shooting continues]
내가 이 집을 떠날 때 입을 옷이라고 생각해 그럼 쉬울거야.
What was it?
뭐지?
You look good, you are the best, something like that.
너 멋져, 너 최고 이거잖아.
Yeah, right..
어, 그러니까..그..
You should say that so I can leave this room.
-그거 해야지 내가 나가지. -어, 그니까 그러니까..
Someone usually shouts out the correct line.
이 쯤 되면 누가 크게 읽어 줄때가 됐는데?
- Handsome. Blinding my eyes. The best! - Handsome.
멋있어, 눈부셔, 최고!
Right...
맞다...
- Do it again. - Handsome. Blinding my eyes. The best!
-다시해? -멋있어, 눈부셔, 최고!
Ah, it was too late.
아, 늦었다... 이씨.
The best! [You viewers are the best~
최고!
Of all the idol group members, only Yook Sung Jae for me.
나는 아이돌 다 통들어서 only 육성재.
[Bromance triangle]
두부 드세요, 두부!
[Gong Yoo/Dong Wook/Sung Jae's omitted scenes]
비하인트 기타누락신 개봉 박두
[# Youngest_is_love]
#막내는_사랑입니다
Oh, this must be her number. [Goblin calls Sunny without Grim Reaper's permission]
이게 그 여자 전화번호인가봐.
It's going, it's going.
신호 간다, 신호 간다!
Hello?
여보세요?
[Grim Reaper stops time]
이에 시간을 멈추는 저승사자
Hello? Oh, my! Hello! Hello?
여보세요? 어머~여보세요? 여보세요?
- I like the third one. - How come my trick doesn't work on you?
-나 세 번째. -너 왜 이거 안 걸려?
Isn't it cool? Isn't it neat? I can do this, too, you know.
멋있지 신기하지? 이건 나도 할 수 있거든.
Ding.
땡!
[Up to this is in the script]
응?
What's this? What is it?
이건 뭐야? 이건 뭐지?
Eat it.
먹어.
[Should we tease our baby brother?]
우리 막내 좀 놀려볼까?
[What kind of trick did the Goblin come up with?]
도깨비가 생각하는 장난은 과연?
[Up to this is in the script]
어?
What's this? What is it?
이건 뭐야? 이건 뭐지?
Eat.
먹어.
[Should we tease our baby brother?]
우리 막내 좀 놀려볼까?
[What kind of trick did the Goblin come up with?]
도깨비가 생각하는 장난은 과연?
Freeze!
얼음!
[Compliment him~ Deuk Hwa takes in the sudden ad-lib, what a quick sense]
칭찬해줘요~ 돌발 애드리브 받아내는 센스쟁이 덕화
Good job!
잘했어!
I watched to see how you do it. You did good.
내가 어떻게 하나 봤는데, 오~ 잘했어!
Freeze! [ Deuk Hwa's quick sense was aired just the way it was recorded]
얼음!
I think Sung Jae is so good at reacting to those things.
아, 성재 씨도 저런거 진짜 잘 받아주는거 같아요.
He reacted perfectly. The three of use worked so well together.
-잘 받았어요. -네. -셋이 호흡이 진짜 잘 맞았어요.
Especially our ad-libs...
이 애드립 쪽으로는
Of course, the Super Junior is something.
아, 역시 슈퍼주니어는 다르다잉?
B1A4...
B1A4
[Wasn't it BEAST?]
비스트 아니였어?
Everyone, we know. We're just saying this.
여러분 저 알아요, 알면서 한 얘깁니다.
We know the members names, too.
멤버 이름도 알아요.
Changsub, you... [The Grim Reaper proves himself to be]
창섭이, 얘
Minhyuk. Yeah, I know.
민혁이, 어 알어.
And also Eunkwang.
그리고 또 윤광이.
Of all the idols, I only knew Yook Sung Jae.
나는 아이돌 다 통틀어서 육성재만 알고 있었어.
Only Yook Sung Jae.
only 육성재.
You filmed Big with Suzy.
수지랑 '빅' 찍었잖아.
[ This guy is no help...]
이 친구 도움이 안 되네...
Female idol Suzy and male idol Yook Sung Jae.
여자 수지, 남자 육성재.
They're all the idols I know.
내가 아는 아이돌 다야.
When I look at you more carefully, you look like a desert fox.
자네 자세히보니 사막여우를 닮았군.
[Deuk Hwa is famous as a desert fox among his fans]
팬들 사이에서 사막여우로 유명한 덕화
You look like one of the idols I know. Was it Super Junior?
내가 아는 아이돌을 좀 닮았어, 슈퍼주니어 인가.
Wasn't there a noise that came from upstairs? [Grim Reaper and Deuk Hwa acting]
방금 2층에서 뭔 소리 안 났어요?
- There wasn't. - There was, there was.
-안 났는데? -났어요, 났어!
[Sorry, sorry]
미안, 미안
What happened?
어떻게 됐어?
Woo...
우우우~
[Oh, no, our youngest~ sighs from everywhere]
녹화했어, 녹화했어.
[Ah... BtoB fans, that was a misunderstanding]
아... 비투비 팬분들, 오해입니다...
- You're in trouble. - In trouble, in trouble.
찍혔어, 찍혔어.
I was throwing a hot pack to him. I meant to throw it at the wall, but it flew on his face.
아, 핫팩 던졌는데 등으로 던진다는게 얼굴쪽으로 갔어.
[Goblin realizes what happened after the fact]
뒤늦게 현장 상황 알게 된 도깨비
[Oh, yeah?]
그으래?
[Motioning to roll the camera]
'카메라 돌려~'의 손짓
- It's on. - Are you alright?
-아, 돌렸어! -괜찮아?
Just like that, to inflict me harm...
바로 또 저렇게 저를 음해하려고.
Telling them to roll the tape of "Makings of..."
메이킹 카메라 빨리 돌리라고.
Are you alright?
괜찮아?
[You recorded it, right?]
오, 저깄다.
Let's see.
어디 봐
- Did Dong Wook do that? - Over here, here.
동욱이가 던져가지고
Dong Wook did this to you?
동욱이가 그랬어?!
I heard it. [Recording resumes]
나는데?
[Hot pack aftermath, Deuk Hwa defends himself automatically]
핫팩 후유증... 자동적으로 수비하는 덕화
[Sorry, sorry] [How will this story end?]
과연 이 스토리의 결말은?
What happened? What are you doing here? [Goblin and Grim Reaper walk out of the police station]
어떻게 된거야? 너 왜 연락 안 했어?
Uncle down the hall! Eat some tofu.
끝방 삼촌!
Eat some tofu. [Deuk Hwa takes revenge with tofu]
두부 드세요, 두부!
[Inadvertently he succeeds in retaliation!]
의도치 않게 역습(?) 성공!
He did good. Aigoo, good job.
잘했네, 아이구 잘했네.
[ Let's say we're even with this]
네.
[ #In any case_the winner is_Deuk Hwa ]
#어차피_우승은_덕화
One of the bipolar symptoms is making impulsive purchases.
조울증의 증세로는 충동구매가 있습니다.
As for other symptoms... [Bipolar disorder's symptoms, excessive confidence]
다른 증상으로는
you can feel overtly confident.
과도한 자신감이 생기는 건데요.
Gosh, this is really...
아, 이건 진짜!
Who wants to go to the sauna with me? If you're not confident, forget it.
나랑 사우나 같이 갈 사람? 자신 없으면 말고.
Wow, so stuck up. [Quite plain in their confidence]
와..진짜 과도하다.
I'll challenge.
도전.
This felt like there was something missing.
이게 뭔가 아쉬웠죠. 하다가
We felt as though we were missing something, so we were thinking how we can make it more fun.
저희들끼리 뭐가 아쉬워서 이걸 어떻게 더 재밌게
That's how it worked out. It was so funny.
-할 수 있을까. -그렇게 해서 탄생이 된거구나, 너무 재밌었어요 이 씬.
Totally...
완전히...
He's confident.
자신감이 있는거지.
[What is the result of Goblin's deep consideration?]
고심한 도깨비 회심의 한방은?
- Should I do this? - Right, that's it.
-이렇게 할까? -그래.
It will be so funny. So funny.
재밌겠다!
Cue!
큐!
[Splendidly confident]
위풍당당
Who wants to go to the sauna with me?
나랑 사우나 같이 갈 사람!
If you're not confident, forget it. [ His confidence is felt off the screen]
자신 없음 말고.
Wow, he's too much.
와, 진짜 과도하다..
I challenge.
도전!
[He masters the skill right away!]
그새 스킬 습득!
[Grim Reaper's confident has been raised +10]
저승사자님의 자신감이(가) +10 상승하였습니다.
Ah, geez...
아이 진짜...
[As if planned... Yoo Deuk Hwa's confidence has raised +50]
마치 짠 것처럼 유덕화님의 자신감이(가) +50 상승하였습니다.
[Good job, good job]
잘한다 잘해~!
Sung Jae was good.
성재가 잘해.
[We connect without words~ Perfect chemistry for ad-libs!]
말하지 않아도 통해요~
That's not it...
야 이거!
Since you did it before me...
아, 형이 앞에서 했으니까.
Our ad-lib worked out so well together.
이런 애드립 호흡들이 진짜 잘 맞았어요.
We didn't even have to tell each other. Without getting out of character...
딱히 얘기하지 않아도 각자 캐릭터를 벗어나지 않는 범위에서.
Let's take a look at the monitor and let's hear from our female staff members.
아니 모니터에서 보고 여자들한테 얘기를 들어보자.
If it seems dirty, we won't do it.
이게, 이게 더럽다 싶으면 안 가고.
[It is quite funny...]
하하하하
This is a bit... questionable... will we be okay?
아, 이건 조금 애매한데 괜찮을까?
He's raising his arms, too.
-쟤도 올리네? -쟤도 올려.
[Goblin Gong just saw Deuk Hwa's ad-lib]
덕화의 애드리브를 이제 확인한 공깨비
Is it okay?
괜찮아?
Tell me. Is it okay?
얘기 해 봐.
Match this one. [ Decided to revive the ad-lib!]
여기에 맞춰.
In the end, you...
결국
You're the winner.
위너는 너야.
How you do it at the end... just laugh like you think we're silly.
네가 마지막에 우리를 어떻게 하느냐에 따라..
[Laugh like you think they're silly!]
가소롭다는 듯이 웃어!
[Deuk Hwa was good~]
우리 덕화 좋았어~
It was good.
덕화 좋았어.
Who wants to go to the sauna with me?
나랑 사우나 갈 사람?
Showing his stomach slightly like that is so cute and funny.
난 저렇게 살짝씩 배가 보이는게 너무 귀엽고 웃긴 것 같아요, 저거.
Yes.
네.
If you're not confident, forget it.
자신 없으면 말고, 허.
Wow, he's too much.
와, 진짜 과도하다.
I challenge.
도전!
Your stomach... you all show your stomach like that.
배! 저렇게 다 배 조금씩 보여!
Ah, geez...
아, 나 참.
[Ultimately, I'm the winner]
훗~ 결국 위너는... 나다!
[There are unexpected variables at the location!]
도깨비 촬영장에도 의외의 변수는 있다?!
Surprise guests who visited the film location! [#Surprise visits_ We always_welcome you]
도깨비 촬영장을 찾은 깜짝 손님들!
[#Romantic Doctor_Surprise Visit- Featuring Yoo Yeon Seok]
#낭만닥터의_깜짝방문 (feat. 유연석)
- Hello, Director. - I've been to Teacher Kim's place.
안녕하세요.
I heard you're filming here. [Romantic Doctor Kim, Yoo Yeon Seok comes over to play from the surrounding neighborhood]
찍고 계신다고 해가지고.
This camera was over there...
아, 그러니까 이 카메라가..
It's a hospital set, but next to it  is Teacher Kim's set.
병원 세트 였는데 바로 옆에 이제 '김사부'세트장이 있었거든요.
I finished recording a little early today.
그 오늘은 좀 일찍 끝나가지고.
Thanks, Yeon Seok [Friendly, friendly]
다정 다정
I'm sorry. [Bow]
죄송합니다, 촬영 열심히 하십쇼!
Since you've come...
오신 김에...
Hey, do a cameo here.
야, 카메오 한 번 하고 가라?
Should I do a cameo?
카메오 한 번 하고 갈까요?
Goodbye.
수고하십쇼!
[#Greeting robot_Appears (Featuring Lee Gwang Soo) ]
#인사봇_등장 (feat. 이광수)
[Goblin Gong is rehearsing on a ship]
배 위에서 연습 중인 공깨비
Oh? Gwang Soo. Long time no see.
어 광수야 오랜만이다! 왜 이렇게 살이 빠졌어?
[Lee Gwang Soo]
이광수- 공유의 절친한 후배
You're busy, huh?
바빠서 그러지?
You have to have fun while filming for you not to lose weight.
재밌게 찍고 있습니다.
We're having so much fun.
우리도 되게 재밌어.
Thanks. [Laughter everywhere thanks to Lee Gwang Soo's surprise appearance]
고마워요.
No, don't mention it.
아유, 아닙니다.
Work hard.
수고하십시요.
[Folder Bow]
수고하십시요!
He's so tall, yet his back can't rest since he's bowing so much.
-키가 저렇게 큰데 인사를 하느라고 허리 필 새가 없네요. -우와, 진짜!
[Greeting Robot who is greeting all the staff members]
전 스태프들에게 인사하는 인사봇
[Even saying hi to staff members who are in the back]
안에 있는 스태프들까지 모두 챙기는 중!
Work hard.
수고하십시요!
[Leaving as he says goodbye to the light]
대.다.나.다.
[Last Bow]
라스트 꾸벅
[#Receiving_a bow_is_so hard - Featuring Daebak]
#인사_한_번_받기_힘드네요 (feat. 대박이)
[Daebak's family came for a visit]
무서워해요?
[I'm scared] [Ignoring]
무셔워...
- He's scary. - No, he's not scary. It's Uncle Dong Wook.
- 아니야. 삼촌 모서운 사람 아니야. 동욱이 삼촌이잖아. - 무섭대, 무섭대!
[Daebak, it's Uncle...]
선생님, 선생님!
- He likes you so much, Dong Wook. But he was scared of you? - Yeah, he was scared.
-그렇게 이동욱 씨를 좋아하는데 무서워했어요? -응, 무서워했어요.
I didn't seem like the usual uncle he's used to. He felt so awkward.
평소에 보던 삼촌의 모습이 아니니까, 되게 낯설어 하더라구요.
See? Nothing's there. - See? [Grim Reaper transforms into Uncle Dong Wook after he closes the zipper of his jacket!]
없잖아 아무것도!
See? I'm not scary.
이거 봐 안 무섭지?
- He changed. Go to Uncle. - Come.
변신했지 삼촌? 이제 삼촌한테 안아!
Come here. I'll hold you. [What will Daebak do?]
이리와 삼촌이 안아줄게.
- See? Go to Uncle. He's not scary. - Aigoo... [Daebak finally goes to Uncle]
- 삼촌 안아. 그렇지 삼촌 안 무서워. - 아이구.
- Were you scared? - Yeah.
무서웠어?
Sorry.
미안해.
Soo Ah, look. Uncle changed.
-설야아 이거 봐, 삼촌 변신했어. -미안해~
Say, "Uncle, fighting! You can do it! You can do it!"
삼촌 화이팅 한 번 하자, 할 수 있다 한 번 해주자!
You can do it! You can do it!
할 수 있다!
"You can do it!" That's a saying Daebak is trying to popularize these days. "You can do it!"
'할 수 있다!' 저게 요새 대박이가 밀고 있는 유행어거든요.
You can do it! Like this. [Cute, cute]
할 수 있다! 이렇게
- You can do it. Thank you. - Give me a kiss.
삼촌 뽀뽀해주세요. 고맙습니다.
[Chu]
츄~💋
You got a kiss, too?
뽀뽀도 받았어요?
I'm one of the few men Daebak will kiss.
-대박이가 뽀뽀해주는 몇 안 되는 남자중에 한 명이에요. -오~
- His dad and... - Me.
-아빠랑 -저죠.
Makes me feel proud.
뿌듯합니다.
[ Eun Tak goes out looking for next miscellaneous deleted scenes]
다음 기타누락신을 찾으러 떠난 은탁
Did you see it?
봤어?
Yeah, scared me.
어, 나 깜짝 놀랐네.
What is it? [Next shocking deleted scenes are?]
뭔데?
A kiss.
입맞춤요.
[Deleted scenes from the kiss scene]
어?
[Ah~]
꺄아!
[The kiss scene that crossed between fantasy and romance]
판타지와 로맨스를 넘나들게 만든 키스신
[ Revealing deleted kiss scenes that make your heart flutter even when you watch over and over again]
보고 또 봐도 설레는 키스신 누락장면 대공개!
[#ShinTak_Couple's_First_Kiss!]
#신탁_커플의_첫_입맞춤
What is it? [ShinTak couple is rehearsing]
뭔데?
You know what the prince from fairytale does when he's been cursed. That.
그 동화 속에서 왕자가 저주받고 하는거 그거.
So, what about it?
아, 그니까 그게 뭐!
Why are you holding his shirt all of a sudden? [The director suddenly grabs the Goblin's neck]
왜 갑자기 멱살을 잡으세요.
So, I mean... you know you're going to stand close. [Kissing lessons from ShinTak Couple, 1. Pull his neck]
아니 그니까 그거, 하니까 가까이 가 있을거 같잖아?
Then, naturally... like this... like this. And kiss.
그러면 자연스럽게 이렇게 해서, 이렇게 해서 입 맞추는거.
Pull. Try pulling me.
당겨봐, 일단 당겨봐.
Kissing.
입맞춤.
- Get close like that. - Since she's short... [184cm Goblin, worries about height difference with Eun Tak]
그렇지, 근데 키가 작아서.
- Or you can do this. - Right.
-아니면은 이렇게 해도 돼. 이렇게 있으면.. -제가
- Pull me down? - Pull him down [Kissing lessons from ShinTak Couple, 1. Pull his neck 2. Pull him down toward you]
-아, 날 내리라고? -내리라고.
- Then I totally become awkward like this? - Like this.
-아~ -그럼 난 완전 엉성해지고 이렇게?
Kiss. [As expected, incomplete posture]
입맞춤.
Lips... which pose would look good?
어떤 포즈가 좋을까?
If she tiptoes, I think it's cute. [Goblin is an idea bank!]
얘가 발, 이렇게 들면 귀엽죠.
- Right. - Yeah.
그치?
- Pull and... - Yeah, yeah. [Kissing lessons from ShinTak Couple, 1. Pull his neck 2. Pull him down toward you 3. Raise your heels and kiss!]
-하고 당기고. -그렇죠, 그렇죠.
Like this?
이렇게?
Cue!
큐!
So, what about it?
그니까 그게 뭐?
[This is how this cute kiss scene was done!]
그렇게 해서 완성된 귀여운 키스신!
A kiss.
입맞춤요.
[So sweet~]
아이 달달해~
[Beginning of heart fluttering romance, first kiss]
두근두근 로맨스의 시작 첫 키스
Great. It's great. [I'm happy as I'm watching it]
좋아요, 좋습니다.
[Kim Shin and Eun Tak's shy yet cute kiss scene]
김신과 은탁의 수줍고도 귀여웠던 키스신
So pretty.
너무 예뻐요.
Yes.
-네.. -네.
Move. But how do I go over?
움직이기 없기! 근데 나 어떻게 가?
Get up and go next to him?
일어나서 옆으로 가요?
What's this? Is Eun Tak drunk?
뭐야 은탁이 취한거야?
- A little drunk. - A little... [Eun Tak rehearses the kiss scene]
-약간 취했다고 봐. -취한거겠지?
But do I stand like this? [Slouching]
근데 나 이러고 있어?
- You have to do that. - What if I do this? [Eun Tak has an idea]
-계속 그러고 있어야지. -아니면 이러면 어때?
Like the first kiss, look...
첫 키스요. 그건 꼭 받을거에요.
Like this...
첫 키스 나요.
Wow, really... she's brainy.
야, 진짜 머리 잘쓴다.
[Hidden kiss scene master Ji Eun Tak!]
진짜 머리 똑똑하다.
Pour, fill it up.
따르시오, 부으시오!
You can't move.
움직이기 없기!
[Eun Tak's idea was in display in this drinking stall kiss scene]
은탁의 아이디어가 돋보였던 포장마차 키스신
- That looked really like just Go Eun... - You're right.
저 모습인 진짜로 고은이, 그냥 고은이 같았어요.
Lifting that chair... [So cute~]
저 의자 들고가서.
♬  It's a beautiful life  ♬
♫ It`s a beautiful life  ♫
♬ I’ll be by your side ♬
♫ 난 너의 곁에 있을게 ♫
♬ It's a beautiful life, I’ll stand behind you ♬
♫ It`s a beautiful life 너의 뒤에 서 있을게  ♫
They're doing it one more time...
떼고 한 번 더 하잖아~
♬ Beautiful love ♬
♫ beautiful love  ♫ 좋네요.
Perfect... ♬ If you are in the sky ♬
♫ 하늘아래 ♫ 완벽하다!
[Birth of the perfect kiss scene!]
완벽한 키스신 탄.생!
[#PeeChy Couple's_Kiss scene]
#피치커플의_키스신
[Before the kiss scene, PeaChy couple discusses camera angle]
키스신 전 카메라 각도 얘기 중인 피치커플
Well, we're going to move around.
네, 뭐 왔다갔다 할건데요.
Grim Reaper kisses like that?
키스, 키스를 그렇게 해?
Grim Reaper in this mood...
이런 분위기에서 저승이..
Why not? Can't I move around?
- 왜, 왔다갔다 하면 안돼? - 안 되지!
- Of course not. Grim Reaper is... - Whatever. I'm sure she'll write it in fine.
- 저승이.. - 아 몰라, 알아서 쓰시겠지!
Kiss and then... [Recklessly]
떼었어, 뗐어..
[Sunny just keeps laughing...]
헛웃음 나오는 써니
Don't ever look at me. [As if nothing happened, Grim Reaper is serious when he's acting]
그 때 절대 나를 보지 말라고.
Don't cry watching me walk away.
멀어지는 나를 보면서 울지 말라고.
It's your own feelings... [How did their kiss scene turn out?]
그 때 너 혼자 감정누르고 왜냐면
Your memory is lost.
기억이 지워진다고 했잖아.
♬ I’ll certainly find you ♬
♫ 내가 꼭 찾아낼게 ♫
♬ I’ll recognize you ♬
♫ 내가 널 알아볼게 ♫
Forget all the sad moments [Their past life keeps their love apart]
♫ 니가 있는 곳 어디든 모습이 어떻든 ♫ 슬픈 순간들은 다 잊어요.
And forget me, too.
♫ 꼭 알아볼게 ♫ 그리고 나도 잊어요.
♬ I’ll remember ♬
♫ 내가 꼭 기억할게 ♫
Even this way, I hope you have a happy ending...
이렇게라도 해피 엔딩이길.
♬ I’ll look at you ♬ [The man who wishes for her happiness without him in it]
♫ 내가 널 바라볼게 ♫
♬ Even at a place without you, even if many years pass by, I will not forget ♬ [After losing "him," she loses happiness also]
♫ 니가 없는 곳에서도 수많은 해가 져도 잊지 않을게 ♫
♬ Even your expressions and the way you talk, I'll resemble you ♬
♫ 너의 말투 표정 하나까지 담아갈게 ♫
[The sad kiss scene where she doesn't know the fact that they have parted]
이별을 했어도 느끼지 못하는 슬픔의 키스신
Our kiss scenes were... [Sad feelings of love still linger for these two people]
저희 키스씬은
not under happy circumstances. Well, I guess there was one time.
즐거운 상황이 한 번도 없어서..뭐 한 번 나오긴 했지만.
Ah, at the end?
아, 마지막에요?
But rather than between Grim Reaper and Sunny... [Love that could not come to fruition in this lifetime]
그건 이제 저승과 써니라기 보다는
That was between Hyuk and actress Sunny...
혁과 여배우 써니의 모습 이였으니까.
How was it for you?
어떠셨나요?
I was glad that we were able to see the behind-the-scenes from the parts we couldn't participate in. [Newly discovered behind-the-scenes clips]
저희가 참여 하지 못했던 촬영 장면들의 비하인드도 많이 볼 수 있어서 좋았고,
I keep thinking of things here and there. Oh, at that time...
-새록새록 계속 생각이 나네요. -네.
it was like that. Ah, we took that scene like that...
그랬었지, 아 저 장면 저렇게 찍었었지.
Without any exception, everything was so fun.
정말 하나도 빼놓을 것 없이 다 너무 재밌는 것 같아요.
These behind-the-scenes clips...
이런 비하인드 영상들도
you were so fun and cool that... [Wants to do an ad-lib]
너무 재밌고도 멋지셔서 넋을 놓고 보게 되는 것 같아요.
I want to see all of it, all. Right?
다 보고 싶다, 다! 그죠?
Who are you looking at as you're saying it like you don't even mean it?
지금 어딜 보고 영혼 없이 그렇게 말하는거죠?
Can't you be a little bit more genuine?
조금 더 진심일 순 없었니?
I'm genuine. I'm really being genuine.
-아니, 전 진심 입니다. 정말 진심으로! -맞습니다, 네.
Shall we go on to the next one?
자, 다음으로 한 번 넘어가볼까요?
Recalling Goblin Special featuring first time ever released content.
네! 최초 공개 내용들로 꾸며지고 있는 도깨비 소환 스페셜 이번에는
It's a request sent in by "In Na is my Radish for my Chicken."
-'인나는 나의 치킨 무' 님께서 보내주신 요청사항입니다. -네.
I couldn't relax watching the Goblin. Among the scenes...
도깨비 드라마를 볼 때면 항상 긴장감을 놓지 못했는데요
when Park Joong Hun appeared as a ghost...
그 중에서도 간신 박중헌이 귀신으로 나타났을 때
He was so unexpected that I was so shocked.
-그렇죠. -예상치 못한 등장으로 1차 깜놀!
This ending brought on great responses by the viewers...
이 때 이 엔딩이 엄청난 반응을..
It was so scary. Really scary.
정말 무서웠어요 정말!
I was shocked for the second time seeing his purple tongue.
보라색 혀 색깔을 보고 2차 깜놀했습니다. 그런데
But I heard his purple tongue came about using the Shark ice cream. Is that true?
보랏빛 혀는 상어아이스크림으로 만든 거라는 소문이 있더라구요, 정말 인가요?
"I'm curious about that makeup." He's asking us to satisfy his curiosity.
그 분장의 비밀이 궁금해요, 라고 궁금증을 해결 해달라는 요청사항을 보내 주셨는데요.
It was scary to see him in person.
실제로 봐도 무섭더라구요.
So, we prepared this.
그래서 저희가 한 번 준비 해봤습니다.
Secrets of special makeup and even the best ever CG!
특수분장의 비밀은 물론, 역대급 CG의 모든 것 까지!
Everything you wanted to know... without leaving any doubts...
궁금했던 것들을 한 점 의욕없이 다
we'll reveal them. Let's meet Curiosity god.
공개해드릴 궁금하신, 바로 만나보시죠.
[The winter of 2016, the Goblin pulled us in like gravity!]
2016년 어느 겨울밤 우리를 중력처럼 끌어당긴 도깨비!
[Including casting, costume, props, makeup, etc. Made center news]
캐스팅은 물론 의상, 소품, 분장 등 '연일 화제'
[Cinematography that has never been seen before]
어디서도 본 적 없던 영상미까지
[The strange and mysterious secret of Goblin?]
과연 도깨비의 이상하고 신비한 비밀은?
[We dig into all of the Goblin's secrets]
도깨비 속 모든 비밀을 파헤친다
[Curiousity god]
궁금하신
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 3] Explosive visual! [Makeup, costume]
궁금하신 도깨비 베스트 3
Nice to see you. [The treacherous servant reappears leaving a strong impression]
반갑다.
You must be that Goblin Bride. [The secret behind this hair raising scene?]
네가 그 도깨비 신부구나.
[In the middle of taping the scene with the treacherous servant that shocked everyone]
네가 도깨비 신부구나.
[The makeup team dispatched as soon as they say "cut!"]
여기 위에.
They worked really hard.
정말 고생하시더라구요.
They had to fix the makeup every now and then. Since he couldn't swallow his saliva, he was carrying around a cup.
계속 틈틈히 저거를 수정을 하시고. 침을 삼키지 못하셔서 컵을 가지고 계시더라구요.
[The treacherous servant had to be taken care of often! What is the secret behind his tongue makeup?]
수시로 관리가 필요한 간신! 관연 간신 혀 분장의 비밀은?
There's food coloring you use when making cookies. It's for coloring icing. [Choi Gyeong Hee, Makeup Team Director]
쿠키 만들 때 하는 색소가 있어요. 아이싱 컬러라고.
The color goes on fine on the surface of the tongue.
혓바닥 같은 경우는 착색이 잘되는데
But it won't stick to the side or bottom of the tongue.
옆이나 밑면같은 경우는 착색이 잘 안돼서
We put on one more layer before we took close-up shots.
타이트한 샷 들어가기 전에 거긴 한 번씩 더 덧발라주고
So, the Sunbaenim went through a lot.
그러니까 선배님이 너무 고생 많이 하셨어요.
They put on three, four layers while taping the scene.
색을 매번 입히면서 이렇게 촬영을 했었는데, 조금 힘들었는데
I heard that it takes five hours for them to do Samshin grandma makeup.
삼신할머니 등장하는데 5시간 걸린다는 얘기를 듣고 아주
So, I filmed with a grateful heart.
감사한 마음으로 지내고 있습니다.
[Even the treacherous servant acknowledges difficult Samshin grandma makeup?]
간신도 인정한 더 힘든 삼신할머니 분장은?
We'd meet four or five hours ahead of time.
네다섯 시간 정도 전에 만나서
We'd put up her hair and...
저희가 먼저 머리를 다 올려주고
the special makeup team would put all the peaces on her face. [Lee El's face 3D model]
특수분장팀이 얼굴에 피스를 다 붙여주시고, 마지막 마무리로 저희가
We'd put on her wig. It's a very difficult work. For four or five hours...
가발을 씌우고, 굉장히 힘든 작업이거든요. 네다섯 시간동안
She has to sit still like that.
앉은 자세로 그대로 있어야 되는 거에요.
I was grateful to Lee El.
이엘 씨한테 더 감사하더라구요.
[Grim Reaper is curious about Samshin grandma's makeup]
봐바, 손.
- How did it feel? - It felt like your skin.
-어떻던가요 촉감이? -음, 피부같았어요.
Our special makeup team...
우리 특수분장팀의 또 다른
- there's their know-how. - You're going through a lot.
노하우가 있죠.
People who glued on and worked on my face suffered a lot more.
붙이고 작업해주신 분들이 훨씬 더 고생 많이 하셨어요 제가
When I was in pain, I'd express all that and...
좀, 좀만 아프면 아픈거 다 표현하고
When I was uncomfortable, I spoke up quite a bit...
좀 불편하면 불편하다 워낙 말을 많이 해서
I'm sure it was hard for them.
힘드셨을 거에요.
[In every episode, he showed the perfect coat fashion]
매회 코트 패션의 정석을 선보이며
[Goblin set the trend for long coats for men]
남성코트의 대유행을 만든 도깨비
[There was a day when the fashion leader, Goblin, stunned the producing team]
패션리더 도깨비가 제작진을 당황하게 한 날이 있었는데...
- Wearing... wearing this? - I think the director is a bit stunned.
-요, 요거 입고? -감독님 지금 약간 당황하신 것 같은데?
I told you earlier that I'm wearing burgundy top and bottom.
내가 아까 위아래로 버건디라 그랬잖아요.
- Burgundy? If you say that, how would I know such a difficult word? - Plum color.
-버건디라 그런 어려운 말 쓰면 내가 어떻게 알어.. -자주색! -아~
I usually don't dress so particularly while working on dramas...
저도 원래 드라마 할 때 옷 세게 안 입는데
But while working on Goblin, I want to have fun dressing like this.
요거는 도깨비 하면서는 간간이 한 번씩 재미로 튀려고.
- Just don't use difficult words. - I got it.
- 어려운 말만 안하면 돼. - 알았어요.
- Say reddish color, not burgundy. - Dark color. [Goblin convinces the director who was shocked at his full burgundy fashion]
-붉은 색! 버건디 아니고 붉은 색! -아니 시뻘건 색.
Try taking it. I want to see how it comes out.
한 번 찍어보자 이거 어떻게 나오나 보게.
[Even Goblin was a bit concerned about reddish burgundy look!]
하이, 큐!
- Cut! - Let's see, let's see...
커트. 확인해볼게요.
I've never dressed to stand out like this before.
나 태어나서 이렇게 센 옷 처음 입어봐요.
When will I get to wear something like this if not for Goblin? [Full burgundy fashion that's only possible to try on Goblin]
도깨비 아니면 이런거 언제 입어봐.
[This is how his "Burgundy Fashion" came about at the buckwheat field scene]
그렇게 완성된 공깨비의 '버건디 패션' 메밀밭 장면
[The Goblin makes this difficult scene!]
이 어려운 걸 도깨비가 해냅니다!
Isn't it amazing? [Even the Grim Reaper is amazed that the Goblin can get away with burgundy fashion]
신기하지?
Even the Grim Reaper accomplished such an amazing thing.
저승사자도 그저 신기한걸 했단 말이지?
Do it again. Why? What? I'm competitive. [Grim Reaper doesn't want to miss out on fashion]
다시 해, 왜 뭐? 승부욕이야.
Where do I go?
어디로 가?
What are you doing, Miscellaneously Omitted Person?
뭐하는거야 기타누락자.
It seems like just yesterday you two ahjussis walked toward me stomping.
아저씨들이 쿵쿵 걸어오던게 바로 엊그제 같은데
You were so cool, ahjussis... [Goblin + Grim Reaper were so cool!]
아저씨들 진짜 멋졌는데..
Ah, this scene...
아, 이 씬 정말!
I screamed. I'm sure everyone screamed.
야! 소리 질렀어요, 아마 모두가 소리를 질렀을 거에요.
[Grim Reaper's fashion that's threatening Goblin?]
도깨비를 위협하는 저승이 패션은?
He's wearing a very lowly hat.
매우 상스러운 갓을 썼군.
The dead recognize me only when I wear this hat. [Human eye can't see it]
이걸 써야 망자들이 알아 봐.
Kim Hae Ryung. [It's a way for the dead to recognize the Grim Reaper]
김혜령
Year Byung Shin, Day Woo Soo... [Grim Reaper's trademark, Hat!]
병신년 무수월 김 일
It's you two, right?
본인들 맞으시죠?
I heard the elementary kids are going to school wearing that hat.
요즘 초등학생들이 저 모자 쓰고 학교 간대요.
Wow, that hat was made with really great fabric. [Made in heaven. Watch out for fake merchandise~]
와, 그 모자 원단이 진짜 좋더라구요 그거!
It was made in heaven.
메이드 인 헤븐입니다.
[The Grim Reaper's second fashion item followed by the hat?]
모자에 이은 저승이의 두 번째 패션 아이템은?
Hello, Sunbanim. I'm Kim Cha. [Hint will be given. It's on the Grim Reaper's suit!]
안녕하십니까 선배님! 22기 김차사입니다!
[What could it be?]
과연 뭘까요?
[Did you find it?]
어?
What's wrong? Are you missing something?
왜그러십니까? 뭐 없습니까?
[A fancy brooch for the grim reaper! It's from the world renowned company D]
저승이 만의 화려한 브로치!
When we decided on the brooch in the beginning...
-브로치를 처음에 설정을 했을 때, -네
The director was wondering if it was a flat out too much of a spoiler. But we pushed forward.
감독님께서 '너무 대놓고 스포아니야?'라고 말씀 하시더라구요. 근데 그냥 밀어 붙였어요.
I did feel that way a little bit. "I'm the king..." [Grim Reaper was the king of Goryeo in his past life as revealed in episode 12]
약간 뭐 그런 마음도 있었고. '내가 왕이다' 라는..
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 2] [I want it! I want to buy it!] [Props]
궁금하신 도깨비 베스트 2
[The place that makes your heart flutter whenever they open the door]
문 열 때마다 설레게 하는 그곳
Come in.
들어와.
[Everything you see seemed mysterious in the Goblin House]
눈에 보이는 모든 것이 신비로웠던 도깨비 하우스
- Do you like it? - Could it be heaven? I love it! [Of course, for Eun Tak, it stole hearts of the viewers as well]
- 맘에 들어? - 이곳은 천국일까요? 맘에 꼭 들어요!
Did you decorate it? With delicate hands like that?
직접 하신거에요? 그 고사리 같은 손으로?
I asked as if I was doing everything myself. [Who did the Goblin ask to decorate the interior?]
이걸 다 직접하는 마음으로 부탁했어.
If you were to ask me about expensive props, they'd be furniture usually. [Joo Dong Man, Props Team Leader]
비싼 소품이라고 하면 보통 가구들이죠.
They were antique furniture. So, the most expensive props were furniture. [The Goblin House was decorated with unique and charming antique furniture]
앤티크 가구라서 가장 비싼 소품은 가구들인거 같구요.
Besides that... the sword that was produced just for Goblin?
그 외에 뭐 도깨비를 위해 제작한 칼?
The sword was especially produced for this project. So, you can say that we put in some expenses to produce that sword.
검은 이 작품 땜에 제작을 한거라서, 좀 고가의 금액을 들여서 제작한 소품이라고 볼 수 있죠.
Wow, you're cool!
오~ 멋있다!
[It's a sword the props team made for me...]
소품팀이 정성껏 만들어준 검이라고 이게~
But you know, Uncle down the hall... the dish you just froze...
근데요 끝방 삼촌, 방금 얼리신 그 접시요
Uncle personally bought that dish during the time of Louis XIV.
삼촌이 루이 14세 때 직접 산 접시라고..
[Grim Reaper broke the dish the Goblin personally bought during the time of Louis XIV]
왓!
That's what he said...
했는..데..
When I throw it...
자, 돌려.
[Is this okay? Dishes are breaking nonstop!]
이래도 되나
It had to go outside like that, but the director kept making NGs...
그렇죠, 저렇게 밖으로 나가야 OK인데 감독님이 계속 NG를 내셔가지고..
I have not lived through the times of Louis XIV. I went through Namdaemun market...
제가 루이 14세 때 살아보질 않아가지구요, 남대문을 뒤져서
I bought something similar... looking antique... I bought cheap ones and we broke them.
그나마 비슷한 약간 앤틱스러운거에 저렴한 걸로 구입을 해서 부셨죠.
Around 20,000 or 30,000 won?
2-3만원 대?
[You're watching the scene that came about after numerous "made in Namdaemun" dishes were broken]
여러분은 지금
That one just now was from the time of Louis XIV. [That one just now was bought in Namdaemun market at 20,000 to 30,000 won!]
방금 그거 루이 14 때 접시다!
[There was a prop that was harder to find than dishes from the time of Louis XIV.]
루이 14세 때 접시보다 더 구하기 힘든 소품이 있었다는데...
We needed lots of props that were not in season. [Buckwheat flowers bloom in late summer] [Maple leaves can only be seen in the fall]
시대에 맞지 않은 소품이 되게 많았어요, 메밀꽃 이라던지 단풍잎 이라던지
Among them, as for buckwheat flowers, we filmed the first portion in the summer.
그중에서도 메밀꽃은 초반에 여름에 촬영을 하고
We filmed the second half after we got back from Canada. So there weren't any buckwheat flowers around.
캐나다 갔다와서 다시 후반부에 촬영을 해서 메밀꽃이 없었거든요.
- Buckwheat flower scent. - Buckwheat flower bouquet please! [Beginning of taping, Summer! Goblin was taped at the buckwheat field filled with flower scent]
-메밀꽃내음. -메밀꽃다발이요!
I can smell the scent...
꽃내음이 나네요~
[Second half of the taping, he was recalled to Jumunjin beach in the middle of winter]
하이, 큐!
But what kind of flowers are they?
근데 그 꽃은 뭐에요?
Buckwheat flowers.
메밀꽃!
That's-That's not what I'm asking.
그게! 그걸 묻는게 아니잖아요.
Why are you holding them?
왜 들고 있냐구요.
My mother grew them in the house for a month.
저희 어머니가 직접 한 달 동안 집에서 기르셨어요.
It's my first time hearing that. Really, it's my first time. Really.
처음 듣는 소리야. 진짜 처음이야 진짜!
She brought them to us at the Jumunjin location. Thanks to her, we were able to finish recording.
주문진까지 저희 촬영장에 가지고 오셔가지고 그날 그 덕에 촬영 무사히 마쳤죠.
[Thanks to his mother's work, the buckwheat flower scene in the middle of the winter was born]
어머니의 정성으로 탄생한 한겨울 메밀꽃 장면
What's the meaning of buckwheat flowers?
근데 메밀꽃은 꽃말이 뭘까요?
Lover.
연인.
[Picturesque first meeting of Goblin and Eun Tak completed!]
한 폭의 그림 같은 도깨비와 은탁이의 첫 만남 완성!
This scene was left out, but there's a lamp in the Grim Reaper's cafe.
화면에는 빠졌었는데, 그 저승 찻집에 있는 등이 있어요.
- The one hanging off the ceiling in the middle. - Ah, yes. [This light fixture came from New York across the ocean]
-천장에 달려있는.. -아, 네. -가장 가운데
The director and art director bought it from New York.
감독님하고 미술 감독님이 뉴욕에서 사오신 거 거든요.
Actually, lots of props in the Grim Reaper's cafe are from New York.
사실 저승 찻집에 있는 많은 소품들이 다 뉴욕에서 사온 거에요.
- How about the chime? The one hanging. - Yes, that was bought in New York, too.
-그 종소리 나는 그 달려있는.. -맞아요, 그 종도 다 뉴욕에서 사오신 거고.
That light fixture was very expensive also. So, we were very careful...
그래서 그 등도 굉장히 고가라서, 촬영할 때마다 정말 노심초사하면서
whenever we had to record.
찍었었습니다.
If you watch the scene later on, please pay attention to that.
나중에 이제 또 다시보시면 그 부분도 한 번 봐주시구요.
It's fun to watch again knowing these facts.
네, 이렇게 알고 다시 보면 또 더 재밌잖아요.
That's right.
-맞습니다. -네.
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 1] [Is it a movie? Drama?] [The best-ever CG]
궁금하신 도깨비 BEST 1
[You can't pull it and can't leave it either]
뺄 수도 없고 그대로 둘 수도 없었던
I can hold the sword.
검이 잡혀요!
Wait just a moment. I'll put it out for you! [The sword that was stuck in the Goblin's chest for over 900 years!]
잠깐만 기다려요. 내가 빼줄게요!
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 1] [First CG, Goblin's 900 year-old sword]
궁금하신 도깨비 Best 1
[The secret behind this opening?]
이 뚫린 부분의 비밀은?
[The sword is stuck in his chest while filming!]
자, 스탠바이
Cue!
큐!
Wait just a minute. I'll put it out for you.
잠깐만요, 잠깐만 기다려요 내가 빼줄게요!
[The Goblin is wearing something inside the knit? The secret of the sword in his chest?]
니트 안에 뭔가 입은 도깨비?
It's moving. It's moving...
움직여요, 움직여!
The makeup team and props team worked together to create it.
분장팀과 소품팀이 합작을 해서 만들어 낸거죠.
We made a cast that matches Gong Yoo's body and put on the thick and hard...
공유 씨 바디를 그대로 뜨고 그 이후에, 캐스트라고 하는 제품으로 딱딱하게
It's thick, but we made it light.
두껍게해서 가볍게 만들었어요
So, we made an incision with the drill in the chest area and put the sword in it.
그래서 가슴부분도 드릴로 다 절개를 해서 검을 거기에 꼽았죠.
I've done exactly the same thing in my previous project.
제가 전작에서 저 똑같은 걸 해봤었거든요.
I had to portray a role where the sword comes out of my body.
-아, 네 알죠. -저는 이제 몸에서 칼이 나오는 역할을 해가지고.
I put on that cast and had about 30 swords stuck on it. That's very complicated and it takes a long time.
저 캐스트를 꽂고 칼을 한 30개씩 꽂아 봤는데, 저거 굉장히 복잡해요 시간도 오래걸리고.
And you have to tighten each one of them with the drill.
드릴로 또 하나하나 다 조여줘야 되고
[The Goblin sword is complete when the blood is on it]
-과감하게 해 그냥. -예, 예.
This is the first time I had to do so many things while acting.
아, 나 연기하면서 이렇게 뭐가 많은 거 처음이야.
Really? How about Train to Busan?
그래요? 부산행은요?
This one has a lot. Really a lot.
아, 이게 뭐가 많아. 진짜 많아.
[With the use of CG, the Goblin sword is complete]
화룡점정
Actually, the fire on the Goblin sword is more green than blue.
사실 그 도깨비 불 색깔은 사실 푸른색 보다는 약간 녹색에 좀 더 가까운 푸른색이 거든요.
Red looks too strong and too intense. And blue looks too cold.
빨간색은 너무 좀 세보이고요 강렬해 보이기도하고 푸른색은 좀 차가워 보이구요
I wanted the color with some green in it.
그 중간에 살짝 녹색이 들어가는 색을 저는
And that's how we produced it.
원했고 또 그렇게 또 연출을 한거에요.
Like that, in those scenes where I disappear or transport... it's treated with a black afterimage.
저렇게 이제 제가 사라지는 장면, 뭐 제가 순간이동을 하는 장면에선 블랙으로 잔상이 처리돼요.
That's right.
아, 맞아요.
And when the Goblin disappears, the afterimage is in blue like that. All that was intended by the director.
-그렇죠. -네, 그리고 도깨비가 사라지는 장면은 저렇게 푸른빛으로 잔상이 처리되고. 저것도 감독님이 다 의도하셔서.
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 1] [Second CG] [The car cut in half by the Goblin]
궁금하신 도깨비 Best 1
[That of a catwalk by the two men, the most intense scene]
두 남자의 모델 워킹에 버금가는 가장 강렬했던 명장면
Hurry up and go, hurry!
빨리 가,가,가,가. 빨리 가!
[The Goblin cuts the car in half to rescue Eun Tak]
은탁을 구하기 위해 차를 반으로 자른 도깨비
[The secret behind this scene?]
이 장면의 비밀은?
Please anticipate what this perfectly fine car transforms into later.
이 멀쩡한 차가 이따 어떻게 변해 있는지 기대해 주십시요.
[Actors passionately acting in the perfectly good car]
멀쩡한 자동차에서 열연을 펼치는 배우들
[The car is prepared in advance for the filming]
촬영을 위해 미리 준비된 차량
[The identity of this car?]
과연 이 차량의 정체는?
[Actors passionately acting in the perfectly good car]
멀쩡한 자동차에서 열연을 펼치는 배우들
[The car is prepared in advance for the filming]
촬영을 위해 미리 준비된 차량
[The car is split in half?]
어머, 어머
They prepared two of the same car.
같은 차를 두 대 준비했어요.
One car is fine and the other one is...
그래서 한 대는 멀쩡한 차고, 한 대는 이미 다
already cut in half...
-잘려져 있는 걸 가지고 와서 -반으로?
Wow, amazing.
이야, 대단하다.
They cut it so much better than I had expected. I was so surprised.
생각보다 너무 잘 잘라주셔서 너무 놀랐습니다.
And with CG, we added fire or sparks in other areas...
그리고 자른 부위에 CG로 저희가 불 티라던가 스파크라던가
We made it seem as though it was just cut. We made it very realistic.
또 방금 잘랐단 느낌을 또 연출을 해서요, 더 사실감있게 만들었어요.
[Staff members are pulling the car using a rope]
자동차를 줄로 연결해서 끌고 있는 스탭들
Since the car that's cut up can't move by itself...
근데 이 잘려져 있는 차들은 직접 움직일 수가 없으니까
You can't drive it, so they put the training wheels on and pulled it by hand...
운전이 안되니까 밑에 바퀴를, 보조바퀴를 달아서 이렇게 손으로 끌면서..
Like that... [Back to where they started manually]
다시 제자리도 수동으로
Yeah...
네...
[The scene where the car falls when the Grim Reaper leaning against it steps away from it]
자동차에 기대어 서 있던 저승이가 움직이면 차가 쓰러지는 장면
[What really happened?]
큐!
[They put a rope on the car and pulled it to make it fall]
자동차에 줄을 달아 당겨서 쓰러지게 함
[Did it fall okay?]
잘 쓰러졌나?
[Curiosity god, Goblin Best 1] [Third CG ] [The ship the Goblin sunk]
궁금하신 도깨비 Best 1
[The best scene in Goblin where the ship sinks]
연일 화제가 된 도깨비 속 BEST 명장면 배 침몰신
[Everyone was surprised at the cinema-like details]
영화같은 디테일에 모두가 놀란 명장면
Save me!
살..살려주세요!
It's too late.
늦었다.
[How did they make this scene?]
이 장면은 어떻게 만들어졌을까?
Wow, we finally have the scene with the ship. I thought this scene was so cool... [Grim Reaper's voice gets louder when his favorite scene comes up]
와, 드디어 이제 배 씬이 나오네요. 전 이 씬 정말 너무 멋있어서
I was so curious even before the episode aired.
굉장히 궁금했어요 방송 보기 전에.
Even from the highlight scene... it's one of my favorite scenes.
하이라이트 때 부터 정말 너무너무 제가 좋아했던 씬 중에 하나에요.
[This construction site is the Goblin location?]
건축 현장 같은 이 곳이 도깨비 촬영장?
Is this the most steep angle for this scene?
지금 이 정도 들리는게 제일 들리는 거에요?
[Inside a large water tank, the ship is almost standing up!]
대형 수조 안, 거의 수직으로 들려 있는 배!
People will fall in and when you hit it down with the sword, it will blow up...
사람들 다 빠지고 마지막에 칼로 내려치면 폭파하고.
[The preparation began in the day and the recording goes into the late night]
대낮부터 준비해서 늦은 시간까지 계속되는 촬영
Wow, it's really gigantic.
와, 정말 어마어마하네요.
Yes, they made the ship.
네, 배를 만들었어요.
Yes, I heard it was very expensive to make it.
네, 저 비용도 정말 어마어마하게 들었다고
Yes, from what I heard it cost enough to make an entire episode.
-들었어요. -제가 알기로는 거의 한 회 제작비가 들었다는 걸로 알고 있어요.
So many people worked so hard for this. [Thanks to so many staff members' hard work, the spectacular scene came together]
정말 많은 분들이 고생하셨어요.
Our stunt team and martial arts team really suffered.
네, 우리 스턴트맨들 무술팀들 진짜 고생 많았어요.
[Recording in the large water tank]
네
[Combining the blue screen set to produce the sinking ship scene!]
대형 수조에서의 촬영과 블루 스크린 세트장 촬영을 혼합해 해 침몰 장면 연출!
[The filming where the combination of ship's movement, actors acting, and special effects are important]
배의 움직임, 배우들의 연기, 특수효과의 조합이 중요한 촬영
The recording is divided into the time before the Goblin gets angry and after he gets angry.
촬영은 도깨비가 분노하기 전과 분노한 후로 나뉘어져 있어요.
So, before he gets angry, they built a ship model on the set
그래서 분노하기 전에는 사실 기본 세트장에서 배를 실제로 모형을 만들어 놓고
and that's how the recording proceeded. And after he gets angry, the ship starts to tilt.
촬영이 진행이 되었구요, 또 분노한 후에는 배가 조금씩 기울어 져야돼요
So, the part where the ship tilts, we actually tilted the ship at an angle in the water tank set and proceeded with the recording.
그래서 그 기울어 지는 부분은 저기 수조세트에서 배를 실제로 기울여 놓은 다음에 촬영이 진행이 되었어요.
Besides the ship and characters, waves, backgrounds, and fire that catches on the body...
배와 인물빼고는 뭐 파도라던가, 뭐 배경이라던가 몸에 붙는 불
The fire on the sword and etc... we had to do all that in CG.
칼에 붙는 불, 뭐 등등 모든 것을 CG로 다 제작했어야 됐기 때문에
It took a lot of time and concentrated efforts.
굉장히 시간이 많이 가고, 또 공이 많이 들었던 것 같습니다.
- Wow, isn't the scale grand? - Wow!
야, 진짜 대단한 스케일 아닙니까?
So, it took about a week to record that. I'm so proud.
이래서 거의 일주일을 촬영을 했던..정말 자랑스럽습니다.
The viewers don't think it's CG when it comes to that.
시청자들은 CG라고 생각을 못 해. 그런거
They do think the ocean is CG.
바다는 CG라고 생각을 하지
But they ask how big is the set...
세트장이 얼마나 크길래, 막 이러더라구요.
So, it's not fair for the CG team.
CG팀은 억울하지.
Our drama is a CG drama.
우리 드라마 CG드라마 인데.
We still have time to see great scenes and great lines from Goblin.
도깨미 속 명장면 명대사를 볼 수 있는 시간이 아직도 기다리고 있습니다.
We have prepared the second part of the Great Scenes and Great Lines Awards part 2.
1부에서 보여드렸던 명장면 명대사 어워즈의 두 번째 시간이 또 준비 되어 있죠?
So-called Goblin Nation God Installation Part 2. Let's meet them now.
네, 이름바 도깨비나라 신 임명식 2부. 지금부터 바로 만나보시죠.
Even in small things, God was in it listening to everything. [God voice, Kwon Hyuk Soo, actor and voice actor]
아주 작은 것에도 신이 깃들어 있으므로, 늘 듣고 있었다.
The story of the Goblin that stayed with you for the last 51 days.
51일 동안 그대들 곁에 머물렀던 도깨비 이야기.
You will never forget any of the scenes.
그 어떤 장면도 잊히지 않으리라.
Today, at last, I chose...
오늘은 마지막으로 내가 선택한
I reveal the great scenes and great lines.
명장면 명대사를 공개한다.
This also is the last prize I give to you in this life.
이 역시 내가 이승에서 내리는 마지막 상이다.
[Makes me cry scene candidate 1 – After regaining her memory in nine years, Eun Tak calls out for the Goblin and cries her heart out]
♫ 내가 꼭 기억할게 내가 널 바라볼게 ♫
I miss you... [At the sight of Eun Tak crying out saying she misses him, even the viewers felt like crying]
♫ 잊지 않을게 ♫ 보고싶어!
Where are you...
♫ 자꾸 모두 잊어 버리게 돼 ♫ 어딨어?!
I miss you...
보고싶어!!
I have all the wrong answers. But I do hope this is a right answer. [Makes me cry scene candidate 2 – Even their kiss scene was sad, Sunny and Grim Reaper!]
모든게 오답인 제가 제발 이건 정답이길..
Forget all the difficult and sad moments. [The wait was long, but their time together was too short. PeaChy couple's sad parting scene]
힘들고 슬픈 순간들은 다 잊어요.
And forget me, too...
그리고 나도 잊어요.
At the least, I hope you can have a happy ending this way...
당신만은 이렇게라도 해피엔딩이길.
How could this be...
어떻게 이렇게..
How could you do this to me...
너 나한테 어떻게 이렇게..
I'm sorry...
미안해요.
I'm so sorry...
정말 미안해요.
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
-축하합니다. -감사합니다.
I didn't expect it at all... [Pretty Go Eun who says her face is slightly swollen due to taping all night!]
예상치 못했던 급 오열인데
Thank you for giving me an award.
상까지 주셔서 너무 감사드리구요.
The portions we recorded in Quebec were beginning portions and...
퀘백에서 촬영했던 부분들은 초반이었기도 했고
they were difficult and got me concerned, but...
좀 어렵기도하고 고민도 많이 했었는데
It seems like people liked that scene...
특히나 그 장면을 좋아해 주셨던 것 같아서
I thank you.
감사드립니다.
The goblin that wakes up like that to be immortal... [Where is chic Lee El? The miracle of makeup!]
그렇게 불멸로 다시 깨어난 도깨비는
Bring me the list with this child's name in it.
이 아이 이름 적힌 명부있으면 갖고 와봐.
Then, I'll let her go.
그럼 내 내줄테니까.
How many times must I say... [Difficult Scene candidate 2 – Ji Eun Tak who had to get hit and get rained on without an umbrella from her first taping]
도대체 몇 번을 얘기해야..
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
이따구로? 이따구로? 이따구로?
Give it to me. It's mine, so give it to me.
주세요, 제꺼니까 주세요.
What the heck...
또야?
[Congratulations]
와!
Wow, you're really giving this to me? I can take it with me? Wow!
이거 저 진짜 주시는 거에요? 제가 데려가도 돼요?
I think it was the makeup. Thank you.
분장 덕인 것 같아요, 감사합니다.
There are many other people who suffered in cold weather.
다른 더 추위와 싸우시며 더 고생하신 많은 분들이 계신데 제가 받아서
I feel bad that I won it, but thank you.
죄송하지만 감사합니다.
Samshin grandma, Samshin unni, Samshin noona... thank you for your love.
삼신할머니, 삼신언니, 삼신누나 사랑해주셔서 너무 감사하구요
All of you, each and every one of you, when I created you...
여러분 모두 한 분 한 분 점지할 때
I was happy.
행복했습니다.
You must be that Goblin Bride.
네가 그 도깨비 신부구나.
Pray desperately with all your heart. [Surprising Scene candidate 2:  Samshin grandma returns to her youth as Samshin unni]
염원을 담아 간절히 빌어.
Deuk Hwa, you...
덕화 너..
God only asks questions. The destinies are questions I throw at them.
신은 그저 질문하는 자 일뿐, 운명은 내가 던지는 질문이다.
As for answers... you guys look for them.
답은 그대들이 찾아라.
[Congratulations, Deuk Hwa!]
와! 우와!
Is this the award?
이게 상인가요?
Why is this the award?
이게 왜 상이에요?
As the third generation chaebol, I expected to receive an award like this.
음, 뭐 재벌 3세로써 이정도 상 정도는 받을 수 있다고 예상을 했구요.
Well, I feel like I reaped what I sowed in my hard work. I'm proud.
뭐 열심히 한 만큼 그만한 대가가 온 것 같아서 뿌듯하네요.
[On Target Scene candidate 1: Eun Tak pulled the words right out of my mouth, "I'll marry you, Ahjussi."]
아저씨 능력이 이 정도면 저 결심했어요.
- What? - I made up my mind.
-뭘? -맘 먹었어요 제가.
I'll marry you, Ahjussi.
저 시집갈게요 아저씨한테.
I love you.
사랑해요~
I knew it wouldn't work... [On Target Scene candidate 2: Grim Reaper dreams of happy ending, "Shall we break up?"]
안될 줄 알면서
I dreamed of happy ending.
해피엔딩을 꿈꿨습니다.
But as expected, it's a tragedy.
하지만 역시 비극이네요.
Shall we break up?
우리 그만 헤어질까요?
[On Target Scene candidate 3: Goblin Kim Shin's inner confession, "She was my first love"]
심장이 하늘에서 땅까지 아찔한 진자운동을 계속하였다.
She was my first love.
첫사랑이었다.
Thank you. It's me, me. [ Congratulations! ] [ Recalled Goblin, It's nice to see you again ]
감사합니다! 메밀군. 저죠, 저.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
The poem itself was so nice to begin with.
그 시 자체도 워낙 좋았었고 그리고
In a way, I felt it was suitable for Eun Tak and Kim Shin's relationship...
어떻게 보면 은탁이와 김신의 관계에 있어서 굉장히 적절한?
- Yes. - I believe it was the poem.
네, 시 였다고 생각을 해요.
All I did was just put my spoon on a well prepared table.
저는 그냥 숟가락만 얹은 것 같아요.
Anyway, with so many things fitting in well...
아무튼 그런 그 여러가지들이 잘 고루 맞춰져서
I believe I was able to receive this award.
제가 이 상을 받을 수 있게 된 것 같습니다.
I think people who deserve the awards received them.
-다 받을만한 분들이 받았다, 라는 생각이 드네요. -네.
It was so fun. The names of the awards.
너무 재밌네요 근데 상들이.
They were perfect.
적절했던 것 같습니다.
Full of great content...
알차게 꽉 꽉 채워보내드렸던
Goblin Recall Special part 2. With our last greeting...
도깨비 소환 스페셜 2부, 저희의 마지막 인사와 함께
I believe the drama will be safely recalled to the other world.
비로소 드라마도 안전하게 저승을 소환이 될 것 같습니다.
I'm so sad and regretful to hear you say "our last."
마지막이라고 얘기하니까 너무 아쉽고 슬프네요.
Isn't there season 2 or something?
시즌 2같은건 없는 건가요?
Season 2? I'm not sure. Well, who knows?
시즌 2요? 글쎄요, 또 혹시 모르죠.
No one knows what will happen.
어떤 일이 발생할지는 아무도 모르는 거니까.
Please don't forget our drama and keep it in your hearts for a very long time.
-네. -이렇게 해서 저희 드라마 잊지 않고, 오래오래 마음속에 간직해주셨으면 좋겠습니다.
Thank you so much for your love. We'll say our goodbyes now.
네, 그 동안 사랑해주셔서 감사하구요. 저희는 이만 인사드리도록 하겠습니다.
Everyone, goodbye!
네, 여러분 모두 안녕!
Bye!
안녕!
Thank you!
감사합니다!
Okay, you worked hard!
오케이, 고생했어요.
Fun drama, Goblin... thank you for your love.
도깨비라는 드라마, 재밌는 드라마 사랑해주셔서 감사하고
Thank you for taking care of us.
보살펴주셔서 너무 감사합니다.
It would be nice to visit you again as a different character and appearance.
다른 모습으로 또 다른 사람으로 또 찾아 뵐 수 있으면 좋겠어요.
All the days spent with you were good.
너와 함께한 모든 날이 좋았다.
Every moment I was acting, I was so happy. It was the best.
그동안 연기하는 모든 순간 행복했습니다. 최고!
It will probably be the character and drama I will never forget for the rest of my life.
아마 죽을 때 까지 잊지 못할 캐릭터고 드라마가 되지 않을까 생각합니다.
That's how much I love this project.
그만큼 제가 사랑하는 작품인 것 같아요.
Everyone, please don't forget Goblin too fast.
그래서 여러분들도 도깨비 너무 빨리 잊지 말아주세요.
Lonely yet brillant...
쓸쓸하고 찬란했던
Strange yet beautiful. It was like that.
이상하고 아름다웠던 그런 시간이였습니다.
I will do my best to show you good work in the future.
앞으로도 좋은 모습 많이 보여드리도록 노력하겠습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다!
Bye.
안녕!
One, two, three! [ Wating for those who will stay by our side once again ]
둘, 셋!
Today... what? What?
에이 뭐래!
I want to, wanna, wanna, wanna... have her leave...
내보내고, 내보고, 내보, 내보, 내보, 내보, 내보내고 싶어서 죽겠네 지금.
Goblin underwear... Strong and...
도깨비 빤스는 튼튼해요~ 질기고도~
Thank you. Be nice.
감사합니다. 예쁘게 봐주십시요.
Wait.
다시 한 번!
On this side, a pastel tone fireplace... fire...
이 쪽에 파스텔톤 벽날로..벽난..
What we saw before...
전에 봤던 카페..
Do it again.
다시 해야 돼.